[{"QN":"1","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is not correct about ARTs – Agile Release Trains ","A":" Synchronized on a common cadence, a Program Increment","B":" A virtual organization of 5-12 scrum teams","C":" Are organized around the flow of value and continuously delivery value","D":" Aligned to a common mission via a single program backlog","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"2","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Select best matched scaled event with respect to team event.","A":" Inspect & Adapt – Iteration retro","B":" PI Planning – Backlog refinement","C":" Inspect & Adapt – Iteration Review","D":" PI planning – prepare for PI planning","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"3","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Strategic Themes influences all the following except?","A":" Portfolio Kanban and Portfolio backlog","B":" Value stream budgets and guardrails","C":" Preparing for PI planning","D":" Portfolio vision","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"4","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is the primary purpose of building incrementally with fast, integrated learning cycles?","A":" Integration creates knowledge from uncertainty with faster learning","B":" Provides time and space for creativity","C":" Decentralize decision-making","D":" To increase release frequency","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"5","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is difference between Cadence and Synchronization?","A":" Both have same meaning and can be used interchangeably","B":" Cadence is used to set release frequency while synchronization is for release on demand","C":" Cadence is used to limit the accumulation of variance and synchronized events are used to facilitate cross-domain trade-offs","D":" Cadence is used at Program Level while Synchronization at Portfolio level","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"6","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Based on management review and problem-solving meeting during PI planning, following possible changes are discussed. Which one is unlikely change?","A":" Adjustment to vision","B":" Changes to scope","C":" Technical debt prioritization","D":" Movement of people","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"7","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Inspect and Adapt event has three parts. Identify the one which is not part of it.","A":" The PI system demo","B":" Quantitative Measurement","C":" Problem-solving workshop","D":" Design Thinking Workshop","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"D"},{"QN":"8","Type":"MCQ","Question":"One of the SAFe principles is “Decentralize decision-making”. Which one of the following is the characteristic of Decentralized decision?","A":" Long-lasting","B":" Time-critical","C":" Unlikely to change at least in short term","D":" Leadership decisions","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"9","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which is not derived from the principle “Apply Systems Thinking”?","A":" The solution itself is a system","B":" Do not consider the money already spent","C":" The enterprise building the system is a system too","D":" The value of a system passes through its interconnections","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"10","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which statement is most accurate about PI planning?","A":" If you are not doing it, you are not doing SAFe","B":" Train everyone, launch trains.","C":" It must be preceded by pre and post PI planning event","D":" Key output of PI planning event is – Team PI objectives and program risks","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"11","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Program risks are discussed and categorized into ROAM. Identify the incorrect category.","A":" Resolved","B":" Owned","C":" Assigned","D":" Mitigated","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"12","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one is not the SAFe’s four core values?","A":" Program Execution","B":" Transparency","C":" Build-in Quality","D":" Apply Systems Thinking","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"D"},{"QN":"13","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What does Innovation and Planning (IP) iteration enable?","A":" Integrate the complete solution","B":" Buffer time to improve quality","C":" Advance planning for holidays","D":" Time for Retrospective for each team","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"14","Type":"MCQ","Question":"“No useful improvement was ever invented at a desk.” Which of the following best describes this sentence?","A":" Continuous improvement","B":" Embracing Agility","C":" Gemba","D":" Innovation Accounting","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"15","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is not correct for the “Take an economic view” SAFe principle?","A":" Delivery early and often","B":" Delivery value incrementally","C":" Understand solution economic trade-offs","D":" Work on Shortest Job First (WSJF)","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"D"},{"QN":"16","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is the purpose of “Operational Value Stream”?","A":" Used to build the systems and capabilities","B":" Used to deliver end customer value","C":" Understand the development value stream they support","D":" Help understand Strategy Agility","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"17","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which of the following is not the responsibilities of System Team?","A":" Create and maintain the continuous delivery pipeline toolchain","B":" Attend other team’s stand-ups to support daily activities","C":" Perform manual testing and run automated tests for new features","D":" Use pairing and other practices for frequent review","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"D"},{"QN":"18","Type":"MCQ","Question":"With respect to DevOps, which of the following statements are true? A: DevOps is a culture and mindset. B: Improves the Mean Time to Release (MTTR)","A":" Statement A","B":" Statement B","C":" Statement  Both A & B","D":" None","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"19","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is the advantage of Reducing batch size?","A":" Lower cost","B":" Higher predictability","C":" Higher utilization","D":" Higher variability","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"20","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which principle most accurately describes – “we cannot possibly know everything at the start”","A":" Take an economic view","B":"Apply systems thinking","C":" Assume variability, preserve options","D":" Build incrementally with fast, integrated learning cycles","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"21","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one is NOT a scaling framework?","A":" Daily Scrum","B":" Scrum@Scale","C":" LeSS","D":" Nexus","E":" SAFe","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"22","Type":"MCQ","Question":"RTE is -","A":" Release Train Engineer","B":" Release Train Expert","C":" Release Test Engineer","D":" Reliable Test Engineer","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"23","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Minimum frequency of Delivery/Release expectation in SAFe is at atleast -","A":" Every Week.","B":" Every month.","C":" Every PI (Program Increment)","D":" Every quarter.","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"24","Type":"MCQ","Question":"System Team in an ART performs -","A":" building and using the Agile development environment infrastructure","B":" integrating assets from Agile teams","C":" assists in building and supporting the Agile development environment","D":" All of the above","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"25","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is the allowed no. of people in an Agile Team in SAFe?","A":" 3 to 9","B":" 5 to 9","C":" 3 to 11","D":" 5 to 11","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"26","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Who all from below are NOT participants of PI Planning Meeting?","A":" Business Owners","B":" RTE & Scrum Masters","C":" Dev Teams","D":" UX & Architect Teams","E":" Product Management","F":" None of the above","CorrectOption":"F"},{"QN":"27","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Last Iteration in a PI is typically -","A":" Planning & Innovation Iteration","B":" Innovative Planning Iteration","C":" Innovation & Planning Iteration","D":" Intensive Planning Iteration","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"28","Type":"MCQ","Question":"The Release Train Engineer (RTE) is a ______ and _____ for the Agile Release Train (ART).","A":" Scrum Master - Facilitator","B":" Servant Leader - Program Manager","C":" Servant Leader - Coach","D":" Program Manager - Facilitator","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"29","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one is NOT one of Seven Core Competencies of the Lean Enterprise defined by SAFe -","A":" Continuous Learning Culture","B":" Organisational Agility","C":" Team and Technical Agility","D":" Agile Product Delivery","E":" Leadership Agility","F":" Lean Agile Leadership","CorrectOption":"E"},{"QN":"30","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one of below is NOT a Scrum Master responsibility?","A":" Facilitates team meetings.","B":" Eliminates or help eliminate impediments.","C":" Promotes SAFe quality practices.","D":" Supports the Product Owner in their efforts to manage the backlog.","E":" Manage Development Team.","F":"","CorrectOption":"E"},{"QN":"31","Type":"MCQ","Question":"The Team Backlog contains user and enabler Stories that originate from the ART Backlog & stories that arise from local context of the team.","A":" True","B":" False","C":"","D":"","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"32","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Backlog for Essential SAFe is called as","A":" ART Backlog","B":" Essential Backlog","C":" Iteration Backlog","D":" Sprint Backlog","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"33","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Total number of teams and people in Essential SAFe are -","A":" 4 to 12 Teams and 100 to 125 People","B":" 5 to 12 Teams and 100 to 150 People","C":" 5 to 12 Teams and 50 to 125 People","D":" 5 to 15 Teams and 100 to 150 People","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"34","Type":"MCQ","Question":"PI - Program Increment is typically consists -","A":" 8 to 10 weeks duration","B":" 5 Iterations","C":" 2 Days PI Planning","D":" All of the Above","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"D"},{"QN":"35","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is full form of SoS in scaling scrum terminology?","A":"What is full form of SoS in scaling scrum terminology?","B":" Scrum of Scrums","C":" Scrum Master of Scrum","D":" Scrum of Scrum Masters","E":" Scrum of Many Scrums","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"36","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Program Increment (PI) Planning is a cadence-based event that serves as the heartbeat of the ________________ .","A":" Scrum of Scrum","B":" Program Increment","C":" Agile Release Train (ART)","D":" Iterations","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"37","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one of following is not a SAFe Value?","A":" Transparency","B":" Inspection","C":" Alignment","D":" Built in Quality","E":" Program Execution","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"38","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one is the smallest configuration of SAFe?","A":" Large Solution","B":" Essential","C":" Full","D":" Portfolio","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"39","Type":"MCQ","Question":"SAFe is an","A":" Agile Process","B":" Agile Framework","C":" Agile Methodology","D":" Agile & Scrum Methodology","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"40","Type":"MCQ","Question":"In SAFe you can NOT deliver/release to market before a PI is over. (True/False)","A":" True","B":" False","C":"","D":"","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"41","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one is the smallest configuration of SAFe?","A":" Large Solution","B":" Full","C":" Essential","D":" Portfolio","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"42","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Total number of teams and people in Essential SAFe are -","A":" 4 to 12 Teams and 100 to 150 People","B":" 5 to 12 Teams and 100 to 150 People","C":" 5 to 12 Teams and 100 to 125 People","D":" 5 to 15 Teams and 100 to 150 People","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"43","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Extension of RTE is","A":" Release Train Engineer","B":" Release Train Expert","C":" Release Test Engineer","D":" Reliable Test Engineer","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"A"},{"QN":"44","Type":"MCQ","Question":"What is the allowed no. of people in an Agile Team in SAFe?","A":" 3 to 9","B":" 5 to 9","C":" 3 to 11","D":" 5 to 11","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"D"},{"QN":"45","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Backlog for Essential SAFe is called","A":" Essential Backlog","B":" Iteration Backlog","C":" Program Backlog","D":" Sprint Backlog","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"46","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Program Increment (PI) Planning is a cadence-based event that serves as the heartbeat of the ________________ .","A":" Scrum of Scrum","B":" Program Increment","C":" Agile Release Train (ART)","D":" Iterations","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"47","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one is NOT one of Seven Core Competencies of the Lean Enterprise defined by SAFe -","A":" Continuous Learning Culture","B":" Organisational Agility","C":" Team and Technical Agility","D":" Agile Product Delivery","E":" Leadership Agility","F":" Lean Agile Leadership","CorrectOption":"E"},{"QN":"48","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Standard PI - Program Increment (PI) has -","A":" 8 to 12 weeks duration","B":" 5 Iterations","C":" 2 Days PI Planning","D":" All of the above","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"D"},{"QN":"49","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Last Iteration in a PI is typically -","A":" Planning & Innovation Iteration","B":" Innovative Planning Iteration","C":" Innovation & Planning Iteration","D":" Intensive Planning Iteration","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"50","Type":"MCQ","Question":"SAFe is an","A":" Agile Process","B":" Agile Framework","C":" Agile Methodology","D":" Agile & Scrum Methodology","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"51","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Minimum frequency of Delivery/Release expectation in SAFe is at atleast -","A":" Every Week.","B":" Every month.","C":" Every PI (Program Increment)","D":" Every quarter.","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"52","Type":"MCQ","Question":"In SAFe you can NOT deliver/release to market before a PI is over. (True/False)","A":" True","B":" False","C":"","D":"","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"53","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Which one of below is NOT a Scrum Master responsibility?","A":" Facilitates team meetings.","B":" Eliminates or help eliminate impediments.","C":" Promotes SAFe quality practices.","D":" Supports the Product Owner in their efforts to manage the backlog.","E":" Manage Development Team.","F":"","CorrectOption":"E"},{"QN":"54","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Who all from below are NOT participants of PI Planning Meeting?","A":" Business Owners","B":" RTE & Scrum Masters","C":" Agile Teams","D":" Product Management","E":" UX & Architect Teams","F":" None of the above","CorrectOption":"F"},{"QN":"55","Type":"MCQ","Question":"WSJF in SAFe is","A":" Wait Shortest Job First","B":" Weighted Shortest Job First","C":" Weigh the Shortest Job First","D":" None of the above","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"56","Type":"MCQ","Question":"WSJF does NOT consider following while calculating ranking","A":" CoD - Cost of Delay","B":" Job Size","C":" CoD - Cost of Development","D":" Time Criticality","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":"57","Type":"MCQ","Question":"System Team is responsible for -","A":" System and Solution Demos","B":" End to End Testing","C":" Solution Integration","D":" Building Development Infrastructure","E":" All of the above","F":"","CorrectOption":"E"},{"QN":"58","Type":"MCQ","Question":"SAFe Does NOT have Iteration Demos.","A":" True","B":" False","C":"","D":"","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B"},{"QN":"59","Type":"MSQ","Question":"I&A (Inspect & Adapt) Event consists of following 3 parts (Choose 3)","A":" Innovation & Planning","B":" Quantitative & Qualitative Measurement","C":" Retrospective and Problem Solving Workshop","D":" PI System Demo","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"B C D"},{"QN":"60","Type":"MCQ","Question":"Program risks are discussed and categorized into ROAM. Identify the incorrect category.","A":" Resolved","B":" Owned","C":" Assigned","D":" Mitigated","E":"","F":"","CorrectOption":"C"},{"QN":""}]